Hi welcome to unit 9.
So this is the second unit focusing only on javascript no edged him out no CSSA just yet we have this
unit which talks about control flow.
We just learned about the basics of javascript's of primitives variables.
Some of the basic built in methods and we also talked about how we run files and how to use the chrome
developer cons. And this unit we're talking about control flow which is really about making decisions
and controlling the way that our code runs.
So we're going to talk about some really important concepts including IF statements or conditionals
and loops.
And before I dive into these specific objectives I just want to give you a lay for land.
We have three more units after this one.
So four more basic gyroscope units in total before we go back to each timeout and see assess.
And then we add in javascript together and we talked about something called Dom and inflation.
So once we do that we can start making some fun games.
We can start really building applications things that are interactive and that look really nice and
are styled well not just simple console games or javascript basic games but really substantial applications
so we're getting there but I don't need to skip ahead to that.
It might be tempting but trust me it's really important that you understand everything that we're going
to talk about in the next few minutes.
These are probably the most important for the rest of the course.
You might think that they're the most boring or the least exciting reasons for not making something
there's no exciting finished product there's no real payoff.
But if promise if you just wait a few units you'll make it through this section which hopefully is exciting
enough.
We talk about how programming languages work.
We talk about writing logic it's really a creative endeavor in my opinion it's not something that's
as dry or intimidating as it might appear at first.
But the point is that what we're going to learn here is foundational for everything else for no Jay
asked for Express for Jay Querrey for Dominey relation for databases authentication everything that
we're going to talk about in this unit and the next three units is going to carry over to every other
topic in this course that involves Javascript.
So hang in there we'll get to making those games really really soon.
As far as this particular unit is concerned we have four main objectives and they really revolve around
two main categories and two main topics which as I mentioned earlier are conditional statements and
loops.
The first objective is that by the end of this unit I want you to be able to evaluate complex logical
statements.
So you'll be using things like boolean operators and logical operators and comparison operators.
Basically I want you to understand how they work and how they interact and that's closely related to
the next objective which is that I want you to be able to write conditional statements with if else
if and else components.
So three part conditional statements which is how we make decisions in javascript and then the next
two objectives pertain to loops.
So the first one is pretty simple.
I just want you to be able to write for loops and while loops and incorporate them into your own applications
and your own exercises.
So two types of loops for loops and while loops and then the last objective is that I'd like you to
be able to translate from one type to another.
So from a for loop to a while loop or take an existing while loop and turn it into a for loop.
And then of course sprinkled throughout the unit there are a few exercises small projects and Equus