Hi welcome to unit 10 so unit 10 is all about Javascript functions.
Another one those really important components that we're going to use for the rest of the course.
And not only is it one of the most important.
I'd argue it's the most important part of Javascript.
So pretty much anyone who's ever worked with javascript anyone who has any experience with it would
tell you that the one thing that you have to know in order to understand and to work with javascript
well is functions.
Functions are the building blocks of everything and javascript or almost everything.
So this unit focuses solely on functions.
But we're going to get a lot of practice in every exercise every assignment we do from here on out when
we get to know JSM we get J Query.
It's all based around functions.
So lots and lots of practice coming up later in this lesson.
And later in the course.
So we have three main objectives in this unit.
First is for you to write function declarations and function expressions and don't worry I'll explain
in quite a bit of detail what those are and how they're similar and how they're different.
So two ways of writing functions I want you you'd be able to write both of them the next objective is
a little bit more bite size.
I'd like for you to be able to explain the difference between conses not logging something and returning
something.
So return is a special word it is a key word in javascript that does something special that you'll see
in the next unit.
So the last objective is that I'd like you to be able to define your own functions whether there are
function declarations or function expressions own defined functions that can take multiple arguments
and then will wrap up this unit with some more advanced discussions about two topics which are scope
and higher order functions.
So I don't have the objectives for those because they're not technically core to everything we're talking
about they're not central concepts that you absolutely have to understand.
Really I'm trying to make those make the objectives of the foundational the fundamental things that
you have to know before you leave this course.
But scope and higher order functions are two topics that are important.
They're intrinsic to J.S..
I mean talk about them at length in the last two videos in this unit.
So look forward to that or don't skip them if you want.
OK I'll see in the next.